again this is the Angora Vickers
possessing three qualities bhiku is
practicing the unmistakable air and has
laid the groundwork for the destruction
of the tanks what three here bigger
guards the doors of the sense faculties
observes moderation in eating and is
intent and wakefulness
and that's the one and how big used has
a big who guard the doors of the sense
magazines here having seen a form with
the I Vic who does not grasp its marks
and features since if he left the I
faculty unrestrained bad unwholesome
states of longing and dejection might
invade him he practices restraint over
it he guards the I faculty he undertakes
the restraint of the I faculty having
heard a sound the air having smelled an
odor with the nose having tasted it
taste with the tongue having felt a
tactile object with the body having
cognize Dementors phenomenon with the
mind
Vicky does not grasp at its marks and
features since if he left the my in fact
the unrestrained prepared and wholesome
states of longing and detect rejection
might invading he practices restraint
orig he guards and mine faculty he
undertakes inflame to the mine faculty
it is in this way that a big articles
and since faculty essentially straight
that seems to be the that's the
groundwork to begin practicing super
meditation we want you to be free from sensuality
so that you don't you don't necessarily
you don't not at all to go and seek out
beautiful objects and then practice the
sewage
all you need to do is write the center
strength yeah the whole the whole mind
is already geared towards the mistake of
sensuality so even if you're not
actively seeking things with your senses
the mind and the thoughts and the world
at any it's already implying sensuality
so that's why you don't need to go and
prove to yourself or anything like that
you just need to keep restraining until
the knowledge in regard to the nature of
sensuality as fundamentally unattractive
develops and then of course you want
have to prove anything because you've
done it that's how you go beyond senses
when you lose any form of concern with
them so if if a thought comes up
image something that you attract which
will inevitably happen exactly so he
noted for those thoughts inshallah to
become a parent the actual census must
be well restrained beforehand
that's why the Vinaya the sealer comes
first and that whole thing to change
deceive it do you actually see the signs
and features or exactly yeah because
sensuality is rooted in those thoughts
but you're not seeing those thoughts
because you're immediately out with the
senses seeking the pleasure so that's
the whole point of restraint like really
I'm wavering in this train like you
don't give in because if you do you're
undermining your own clarity in you go
to your own central thoughts which means
every time you give in you sort of
induce more obscurity that you have to
undo later so that's why I like seeing
the danger in the slightest fault
because you know how hard it is to
purify it and then how hard it is to
maintain it pure yet that purity is
necessary for any sort of insight that
you can develop in regard to the the the
root of sensuality which is the level of
thoughts so if you want your thoughts
and photos to become apparent to be seen
through as founded upon the unattractive
the senses the actual census must be
fully fully restrained beforehand then
the tender mind becomes clearer that
they attend the mind effective it
sensuality the sensual sensual intent
and so on
or ill-will the same becomes clearer
when the mind when the body and the
senses have been restrained beforehand
so there is absolutely never a reason to
give in to non restraint
if it's non restraint means it's not
done obviously just restraining senses
in itself will not result in you
understand essentiality either you need
to know what to look for how to look for
what I described in the previous talk
you have to see the unattractive
basically in the heart of everything
that's attracted always attracted cannot
stop and become independent from
unattractive but if you don't see that
then yep since the strength is good and
your mind will probably develop some in
various ways but not to the point of
like the right view and the freedom from
sensuality and so on so that you need a
bit more but none of them will be
available to be developed more if you if
you don't have the sense of strength
before potential thought arises and you
pick up the signs of features of that
central thought
you wanna see that that sensual no
matter what signs of features will be
picked up you also want to remain
maintain the perception of inherent
foundations of disgust so no matter
where your mind goes left or right with
those signs and features and prospects
and possibilities the unwavering
perception of it's still very much
always within the container of
unattractive disgust you stop assuming
the external external to it you stop
making it independent from any disgust
which is when the mind gets pulled by a
very sensual craving so that's what we
like you have to see it simultaneously
present not like going like a method a
succession of steps isn't there yet
first to restrain the senses that's as
much as a method as you're gonna get
don't negative method in a sense of you
don't engage with with a sensuality
through your senses and then yes when
the mind inevitably thinks central
thoughts images memories the the signs
and features of something something
beautiful that accidentally came across
the sound the smell aside and so if the
sensor is trained and that you have a
groundwork now which is the level of
those thoughts that are picking up
central signs so you want to basically
learn how to simultaneously see the
inseparable basis of discussed in regard
to any possibility of those sensual
thoughts not this thought that thought
of this particular thought any just
entirely in its nation is the main it's
fully inseparable from the unattractive
it's rooted in it inconceivable from and
that's how you get to know it to discern
it and then you don't have to keep doing
anything because whenever sensuality
arises it arises with its disgusting
heart you can't want it
not even in your imagination anyway and
that's how you would also understand
that all the sensuality that has been in
the past but you did engage it hold this
ensure that you would even get it's
still the same same nature same
everything cannot step outside of this
basis a vessel of disgust is fully
contained in the same sense slightly
difficult but in the same sense how
after other ceases when you see that
external to the five ugly it is
inconceivable that no matter what soft
view we might have what concede it's
fully contained within the arisen
experience as a whole which is
experience of the five angles when you
fully discern that you will eventually
stop assuming any external dimension to
it which is basically the definition of
our God our self its external it's
independent of the five aggregates and
it's the same principle in regards
assuming the external beautiful
independent of the foundation of the
ugly of not wanted of dispersion which
is why both are on the level of appeared
on the other and sensual